<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>JQuery on David Hamp-Gonsalves</title><link>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/tags/jquery/</link><description>Recent content in JQuery on David Hamp-Gonsalves</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidhampgonsalves.com/tags/jquery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Updating Chrome Extension Manifest</title><link>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/updating-chrome-extension-manifest/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/updating-chrome-extension-manifest/</guid><description>This post should really just read: JQuery 1.4 breaks(Refused to execute inline script) when used in Chrome Extensions using the version 2 Manifest. Update to Jquery 1.7 and you&amp;rsquo;ll be happy.
Unfortunately it doesn&amp;rsquo;t, it reads more like:
Last night I decided to cross something off my to do list and updated Foxish(a chrome extension) to use the version 2 manifest that will become manditory in a short while.
For the most part it was pretty painless.</description></item><item><title>Slimming Down JQuery Easing</title><link>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/slimming-down-jquery-easing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/slimming-down-jquery-easing/</guid><description>For simple javascript animations there is always a trade off between code size and visual effects. Recently I was trying to add some visual pizzazz to hour weather but didn&amp;rsquo;t want to incur the overhead of JQuery UI. What I was looking for was just a simple bounce effect on some moving objects. A lighter weight alternative that I considered was JQuery easing but even that seemed like overkill. My solution was to rip out the parts I needed and I wanted to share how easy that process is.</description></item><item><title>JQuery JFeed</title><link>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/jquery-jfeed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/jquery-jfeed/</guid><description>While working on Foxish I needed to parse some RSS/Atom feeds in javascript. Thinking there would be nice a library for this I took a look around and found a couple old libraries and determined that the best of those was JFeed which is a JQuery plugin.
Issues As I worked on the project I discovered issues with the library and since it was last updated in 2007 it didn&amp;rsquo;t support JQuery 1.</description></item></channel></rss>