<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fedora on David Hamp-Gonsalves</title><link>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/tags/fedora/</link><description>Recent content in Fedora on David Hamp-Gonsalves</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidhampgonsalves.com/tags/fedora/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building Dolphin-Emu on Fedora</title><link>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/building-dolphin-emu-on-fedora/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/building-dolphin-emu-on-fedora/</guid><description>Over the holidays I wanted to play some old game cube games to be festive(Christmas means new games). After some performance troubles I noticed that the version of the Dolphin Emulator I was using from the Fedora repos was version 3 and the current was 3.5. Eventually I broke down and built the latest version, which did make my life/performance better.
Bellow is the command to install all the build dependancies and after that the build should go smoothy and you&amp;rsquo;ll be up and running in no time.</description></item><item><title>Install Node.js / NPM on Fedora Core 17</title><link>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/install-node.js-/-npm-on-fedora-core-17/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/install-node.js-/-npm-on-fedora-core-17/</guid><description>This is just a short and sweet set of commands to install Nodejs and NPM on Fedora 17.
Versions Fedora Core 17 node.js 0.8.9 The Guts(go bash go!) sudo yum install openssl-devel.i686 gcc gcc-c++ sudo ./configure sudo make -j2 sudo make install su cd /tmp git clone https\://github.com/isaacs/npm.git cd npm make install exit Most of this was based on an older post I found here.</description></item><item><title>Iterative Javascript QuickSelect</title><link>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/iterative-javascript-quickselect/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/iterative-javascript-quickselect/</guid><description>A couple weeks ago I entered my first AI related contest, hosted by scribd. The contest was great for beginners since it involved a very simple world and control scheme.
At some point in by bot creation process I needed to determine the n-th highest number in an Array. While for such a simple project I probably should have just thrown some loops together and moved on, but since the project was just I started researching the problem and Hoare&amp;rsquo;s Selection Algorithm.</description></item></channel></rss>