<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wowza on David Hamp-Gonsalves</title><link>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/tags/wowza/</link><description>Recent content in Wowza on David Hamp-Gonsalves</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidhampgonsalves.com/tags/wowza/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Injecting Live Metadata with Wowza (1/3)</title><link>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/injecting-live-metadata-with-wowza-1/3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/injecting-live-metadata-with-wowza-1/3/</guid><description>This is the first post in a series about injecting JSON based metadata into a live RTP streams using Wowza Media Server, Adobe Flex and OSMF.
What We&amp;rsquo;re Building Over the course of these posts I&amp;rsquo;ll cover how to trigger a event with associated JSON data from a flash object via a NetConnection which then in turn cause Wowza to inject the related data into the live RTP media stream and then finally to listen for and handle that event on the client side OSMF based video player.</description></item><item><title>Flash NetConnection for Wowza RMI (2/3)</title><link>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/flash-netconnection-for-wowza-rmi-2/3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/flash-netconnection-for-wowza-rmi-2/3/</guid><description>This is the second post in a series about injecting JSON based metadata into a live RTP streams using Wowza Media Server, Adobe Flex and OSMF.
What We&amp;rsquo;ve Built So far in the previous post we got Wowza setup and created a module which will inject our JSON metadata into our live RTP stream.
What We&amp;rsquo;re Building (in this post) In this short post we&amp;rsquo;ll be triggering the injection of metadata from the browser using a flash object created with Flex.</description></item><item><title>Live Metadata Handling Using OSMF (3/3)</title><link>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/live-metadata-handling-using-osmf-3/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.com/live-metadata-handling-using-osmf-3/3/</guid><description>This is the third post in a series about injecting JSON based metadata into a live RTP streams using Wowza Media Server, Adobe Flex and OSMF.
What We&amp;rsquo;ve Built So far in the previous posts(1,2) we setup Wowza and created a module which will inject our JSON metadata into our live RTP stream. Then we created a flash object to trigger the event injection with our metadata from the browser.</description></item></channel></rss>